# 大家好 我們村發現那個 有棧民在種那個羊角蜜喲
Hi everyone! We discoered that the our villagers are, I mean, the villagers are planting the, the horn melons.
# 我們都不知道 就在那裡
We didn't know that. It's right over there.
# 帶了一個桶去
I'm going with a bucket.
# 好多哇 那麼多
A lot, so many!
# 你看 這個
Look! These are,
# 它這個沒搭棚的 這個
these are not put up on fence, those here.
# 在農村 農村人種 種東西就是這樣
In the village, that's how the, the villagers grow our crops.
# 雖然是好 但是 看相不好 但是
Though it's good, but, I mean it doesn't look good, but,
# 質量還是很不錯的
but the quality is really not bad.
# 嗯
Um!
# 真的很好吃哦
It's really tasty!
# 削一下這個
Let me peel this one.
# 這個是有 可以算是有機的
This is org... It can be considered as organic.
# 都沒打過葯 沒施過肥
No pesticide has even been sprayed, nor fertiliser.
# 種下去就不管的
After planting, they're left alone.
# 草又多
So there's a lot of weed,
# 爛掉的也多
the same with the rotten ones.
# 這種都掉啦
These ones have fallen down.
# 來的太遲啦
We're too late.
# 來 拿著這個
C'mon! Hold this one!
# 這樣吃
Eat this part.
# 這搞了一個
She has picked one here.
# 看一下還有沒有
Let me see if there are any more.
# 真的好甜啊
It's really sweet!
# 熟了這個
Alright, this is ripe.
# 哈哈 他搞了一個西瓜
Haha! He has picked a watermelon.
# 不要啦 刘星辰 不要啦 不要西瓜
No more! Liu Xingchen! No more! No more watermelons!
# 摘這個羊角蜜
Pick these porn melons!
# 你看 這個都是熟的這個
Look! These are all ripe, these melons.
# 這羊角蜜 這種就很靚的 這種熟啦
The horn melons, these are really beautiful. These are ripe now.
# 品相不怎麼好的哦 這個
They don't really look good, those here.
# 但是肯定很好吃的 因為它沒有架起來
But they're certainly very tasty, as they've never been framed up.
# 本來這個羊角蜜要架起來的
Normally, these melons are framed up,
# 架起來才好看
so that they look better.
# 可以 這個也是 你看 那麼大條
Alright! This one too. Look! It's so long and big.
# 這個壞的 這個
This is rotten, this one.
# 你看 這有西瓜哦
Look! Here are some watermelons!
# 這幾個西瓜
This couple of watermelons,
# 很小
are very small.
# 現在好多都壞啦
Many are already rotten.
# 這種應該可以 這都苗都 苗都
I think this is alright. This is, even the seedling, the seedling,
# 死掉啦
are dead.
# 這個不知道熟了沒有
Let me check if it is ripe.
# 這個 我們這邊叫梨瓜
This one, we call it "peer melon" here.
# 以前還小的時候
In the past, when I was small,
# 經常去 去摘隔壁家的
I always, always picked them from my neighbour.
# 現在
And now,
# 現在還是
now I'm still doing the same thing.
# 這種香瓜很好吃的 這種香瓜 很脆的
These melons are really tasty, these melons. They're very crunchy.
# 嗯 有點苦這裡
Um! It's a bit bitter here.
# 很香的哦 這個
You know, it's smells so good, this one.
# 怎麼感覺沒有小時候那麼好吃啦
Why doesn't it seem to be as tasty as it was, when I was small?
# 現在還是燙的
It's still hot.
# 本來要
Normally, it should be,
# 進冰箱冷凍一下才好吃
chilled for a while in a fridge. It would then be more tasty.
# 不管啦
Whatever
# 好久沒吃過那麼 那麼香的那個
It smells so good. I haven't, haven't eaten such a nice melon for a,
# 這個 香瓜啦
for a long time.
# 你看 地上都爛了好多啊
Have a look at the ground! There are a lot of rotten ones.
# 都沒摘掉
No body picked them.
# 你看 我們摘點 我們搞點回去
Look! We're gonna pick some, pick some back home.
# 給家人吃
for our families.
# 搞一點 搞點
Let me pick a bit, pick some...
# 嗯 壞掉啦 這個
Um! It's rotten, this one.
# 就搞了那麼一點點
So we've picked a tiny little bit here.
# 我們回去啦
Let's go back.
# 兄弟還送了一點這個
My buddy has also given us a bit of, these are,
# 油果 跟那個芒杆糍粑
"you guo" (fried rice cake) and these are "manggan qiba" (rice cake wrapped in leaves).
# 給我們吃
All are for us.
# 好不好吃 (註︰沒有原字幕)
Is it tasty?
# 這種做的 他們這裡做的很漂亮啊
This one, the ones that they made here are so pretty.
# 像我們做的 哎 真的沒法
The ones that we made are, ay, really,
# 沒法入 沒法入眼
they really hurt, hurt our eyes.
# 真正做的好看的是這種 這個
This one, this is what it should look like when it's properly made.
# 雪白雪白的 看到沒有
It's snowy white, see?
# 非常好吃的 真正好吃的
It tastes very good, really good.
# 上次我們做的好像 這動的
The ones that we made last time were, like, they could move.
# 好啦 叫拾一下 準備回去啦
Alright! Let's tidy up, and get ready to go home.
# 回到半路 看到兄弟家做這個 進來吃兩個
On the way, we see that my buddy is making these things. So I come in and have some.
# 你看 這個是 小的時候那個 我們這邊叫那個
Look! This is, when we were small... Here we call it,
# 窩粑qi
"guo ba qi" (rice crêpe)
# 這個很好吃的
It's really tasty.
# 吃一點
Let me have a bit.
# 下去拿到碗來 下面有碗
Go down there and take a bowl! There are bowls!
# 下面厨櫃裡有
In the cupboard down there!
# 很好吃哦
It's really tasty!
# 有點 有點燙
A bit, a bit too hot.
# 燙得很靚
It's beautiful!
# 燙的沒那麼好 哈哈哈
Not really, hahaha!
# 鍋都不粘
It's not sticking onto the pan at all.
# 倒點香油下去
Put some oil.
# 先是燒點油
She heats up some oil first.
# 燒了油再
After heating the oil, then...
# 這個就是米漿做的
This is made of rice milk,
# 米漿跟韮菜
rice milk and leek.
# 米漿
Rice milk
# 就是那個推出來的
It's like, ground,
# 到上面去磨 磨出來的
it's ground, ground up there.
# 這個是那個推磨 推的
It's ground, using the mill.
# 就是那個磨石
You mean the stone mill, right?
# 加了韮菜
Yea, together with some leek.
# 純天然的哈 沒有其他任何色素的
It's purely natural, without any artificial colouring.
# 再加上花生油
Together with some peanuts oil
# 是 我就在全南就做這個
Yea, that's what I'm making in Quannan.
# 哦 在縣城做這個
Ah! You make these in the county seat.
# 是 做這個搞外賣
Yea, it's for takeaway.
# 你看 這還有一個公雞喲
Look! Here's also a roaster.
# 哎呀 還有鴨子
Aya! And ducks too
# 你看 這還有綠頭鴨哦
Look! Here are also mallards.
# 還有那個
And also,
# 花的那個
those tinted ones.
# 那邊也還有
Some more over there
# 兄弟家真富有 啥都有
My buddy is really rich. He has everything.
# 你看 這了[SIC]還有很多梨[SIC]李樹哦
Look! Here are also many plum trees,
# 李子樹
plum trees,
# 那邊還有梨樹 啥都有 他家
There are also pear trees. He really has, everything.
# 經常來他家做客
Let me come and be his guest more often.
# 啊 還有楊梅樹 看到沒有 幾棵楊梅樹
Ah! There are also some bayberry trees. See? A couple of bayberry trees.
# 好啦 回去啦
Alright! Let's go back!
# 天都快黑啦
It's already getting dark.